Guide to the Bertram Borden Boltwood Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Subject file, 1897-1932; Series III; 21/2" - 1 box
  - Death certificate, Matilda van Hoesen Boltwood., 1909 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Death notices, wedding invitation, and calling card, 1921, 1926, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Diagram: periodic table, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Grade book, 1921-1922 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Graphs of experimental data., undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - International Congress on Radiology and Electricity (Brussels, 1910), delegate to., 1909 December 11 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper clippings about BBB's work, 1904, 1913, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Newspaper clippings re: the Lord Rutherford-Sir William Ramsay dispute, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Photographs: pictures of Boltwood laboratory equipment and data, Rutherford's home, and postcard of various scientists accompanied by letter from H. R. Robinson, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Press Notice: Large Deposits of Radium Ore Discovered in Africa, Released by Radium Chemical Company, Pittsburgh, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Publishers' agreements: BBB and John Wiley and Sons., 1898, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - USA v. Mountain Valley Water Company:
    - legal document, 1917 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - analysis of Mountain Valley water compared with the analyses of various other waters of similar compositions, undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - miscellaneous samples examined for radioactivity by the Bureau of Chemistry, undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - percentage composition of Mountain Valley water compared with the percentage composition of various natural waters of similar composition, photocopy, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - radioactivity of Mountain Valley water as reported by various observers, 1911 March 9-1917 June 4 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - radioactivity of waters, etc., 1917 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - resume of depositions taken at St. Louis, Missouri, and Hot Springs, Arkansas, 1917 July 2-3, 1917 July 5 (Box 8, Folder 31)
- Folio
  Contains materials from Series III. Subject file. The following is an inventory of the materials which were too large to fit in the regular manuscript boxes and were therefore placed in a folio. Each item is also listed in the Register in its appropriate series and box.
  - Chemical tables in French, undated (Box 9)
    box 8, folder 12
  - Certificates of membership:
    - American Philosophical Society, 1911 April 22 (Box 9)
      box 8, folder 11
    - National Academy of Sciences, 1911 April 20 (Box 9)
  - Death certificate, Matilda van Hoesen Boltwood, 1909 (Box 9)
    box 8, folder 14
  - Graphs of experimental data, undated (Box 9)
    box 8, folder 18
  - International Congress on Radiology and Electricity, delegate to, 1909 December 11 (Box 9)
    box 8, folder 19
  - Publishers' agreements: BBB and John Wiley and Sons, 1898, 1902 (Box 9)
    box 8, folder 24